Friends, $4 million was the size of
India's data science market in 2023.
By 2028, this number is going to reach $1.39 billion.
In India, data scientists
at the entry level are getting salaries of up to Rs 1 million, and experienced
professionals are getting salaries of up to Rs 5 million.
But what are the reasons for this crazy
growth? What do you have to learn to enter this career path?
What are the
skills, how to learn them, and what path to
follow? I will discuss all this with you in today's video. I will
discuss all the skills and qualifications to become a data scientist,
look at career opportunities, and
also share a full bootcamp with you, through which you can learn everything from A
to Z and get certification and job
placement. So, if you are
exploring a future-proof career in the field of big data,
then you will get every important information for a beginner
in this video,
so watch till the end.
I have summed up all the valuable information in it,
so without any further delay, let's get
started.  So let's first understand
why there's such a high demand and salary for data scientists. Basically, a data scientist
works with knowledge of many different domains:
statistics, programming, machine
learning, and business. Now,
with a basic understanding of all these domains, one can
become a data scientist. But we're talking about top-level
people, whom I'll cover
with VIP. Along with this, I'll share information about the important experiences of several top-level
data scientists in India,
who have
built amazing careers starting from scratch. This knowledge will be
useful in learning and interviews at big companies. So, get
out your notebooks. The first
step is statistics. Basically,
statistics helps you
understand data, otherwise it's just numbers. It will
help you understand trends, make predictions, and extract hidden insights.
Suppose a company
needs some insights about its consumers or needs to
forecast sales for the coming quarter. This can be done
with the help of statistics. A
data scientist needs a grasp on this so that
you can  To be able to take the right decisions and not
draw wrong conclusions, it is important to learn the basics and make them
strong. If you skip this, you will have to
practice complex concepts as well.
This will make your work easy and accurate.
Work hard on math concepts related to data science. Even if you don't like math,
you will say thanks later. But there is
no need to go too deep into statistics. Focus on strong fundamentals and there is
much more to learn. Brother, an
expert tip is that you will find many software
tools, but you should not rely on them. It is
important to understand the basic principles. Statistics is
not just about playing with numbers; it involves
storytelling. You should be able to use your findings to
draw such conclusions
with which some action can be taken. There are
two important rules to master the skill:
practice and curiosity.
Maintain these and you will definitely be successful
in learning. Now let's move towards the second important step,
which is programming.
Manipulating data with the help of programming, developing models and
handling automation tasks properly.  While
basic programming knowledge is
essential, skills shouldn't be overlooked. The
most popular and widely used languages ​​are
R and
pythonanywhere.com, so focus on these and
work hard. The second
important thing is that it's
better to learn with projects. Third,
learn properly. Coding is widely used, but it's important to
learn the skills and approach required for data science.
Doing just any random coding course isn't beneficial.
Many students make the mistake of
learning from the purpose of data science. If you
want to develop properly with data science-focused skills, pursuing a proper certification
course is crucial, as it
requires advanced skills. This is a continuously
changing field. Furthermore, you wo
n't be able to get a good job with just a BE, BTech, or BSc degree. This is
because it's a specialized field, so
both skills and qualifications do
n't match with general degrees or courses.
If you're looking for learning that's suitable for a beginning-to-high-paying
job, simply
This 11-month online
bootcamp certification from Simply Learn is highly rated.
Currently, its rating is 1. It has
some advantages that will
help you develop smart strategies. The most important thing is that
it offers a master certification
and an
IBM certificate for all the IBM courses included in it. It was
created in collaboration with IBM, so you
get the advantage of a major tech giant. IBM
experts conduct masterclasses
and live Ask Me Anything sessions, which will
definitely boost your CV strength. You also get access to
IBM's Hackathon. Simply
Learn is a great platform. While
courses and bootcamps are available for different fields, this particular
certification was very powerful. I found this particular certification to be very powerful.
You will get a step-by-step
learning path here. First, you will
learn programming essentials, then the
SQL certification course will be covered.
After that, Paa for Data Science by IBM Applied
Data Science with
[music]
python-tk covers 14+ tools
such as Chat, GPT, and Salesforce.  You'll
work on projects like analysis, employee performance analysis, and even classification of songs. These
projects will provide you with hands-on experience,
which is very valuable in the job market.
You
can also read reviews from previous learners here. Secondly,
I was talking about the
importance of staying advanced. I found the generative AI angle to be
very smart. These people are offering live sessions on AI trends,
best tools, and promotion engineering.
With AI, you'll
see that a lot of your work will become easier
if you want to use it. But it's
important to remember that you
can't make the entire work virtual by imposing it on AI. You have to do the
quality control yourself.
Use AI in such a way that you
can focus more on storytelling, decision-making, and
strategic tasks. But yes, you can learn how to
use AI smartly in this certification. The
next important step is machine
learning. Now, people make a big mistake while learning machine learning.
You will learn machine learning
algorithms, but
applying these algorithms is difficult.
How will you get the data for this? For this, you will have to develop an understanding of
what kind of data you need to apply algorithms.
When you do personal projects, you can extract
that data using SQL accordingly. So,
you should know all these practical things, plus it is
very important for you to work. Literally every
expert has said that practice is very important
in the data science path. According to them,
these people are getting more than 25 projects done. Take
them seriously because as a
fresher, these projects will strengthen your portfolio
and profile.
In the next step, two important skills will come,
mainly SQL and SQL. SQL
is another programming language with its help,
work is done with the structured data of the database.
It is considered a universal database
query language. And in all the
data science jobs you see, SQL
is required. As I
told earlier, you will
also come across SQL very rarely in extracting data
in your projects.
SQL has its own importance in Simply Learn's Data Science Certification.
Certification courses are also included. The
second, W, streamlines the data analysis
process.
This is a crucial skill for data scientists
because it increases productivity and
simplifies work. It's a very useful tool for
communicating and exploring data insights. It's a highly
chosen tool in the industry. You'll also
receive training on this tool. Another positive is
that it offers four electives,
so you can choose the latter based on your interests and learning needs.
You can learn and explore as you learn.
This is why I recommend this course.
It covers all skills, offers
multiple certifications, and
also has an IBM advantage, as they
select industry experts to teach. This is why the
curriculum is practical and job-ready. It's ideal for beginners,
starting with the basics and ultimately
earning you a master's degree and IBM certifications, plus opportunities for jobs in major companies.
Job assistance is also available,
but friends, what package you will finally get
and how expert you will become will
depend on your dedication. There is a lot in it. It is
not that only geniuses can learn.
As I said, the
mantra of practice and curiosity is most important.
You have crazy information available on the internet. The
deeper you dive into this industry, the
more you will make the right decisions and your
passion will develop. Apart from this, as far as
learning the right skills in the right way is concerned,
I have suggested you the best courses. You will
also get certificates for all the skills training and strengthening the brain.
So this is a proper qualification to
become a data scientist. So if you
want to start a data scientist career, you can check out the course page.
Explore all the information and
start your journey soon. You will find the
link in the description. Their next cohort is going to
start soon, so check it
out quickly. And here we go. Today we saw
all the steps,
tools, expert tips and valuable information to become a data scientist.  Lessons
which are very helpful for every beginner
I
also discussed with you in detail about Data Science Masters Certification
and saw what benefits you can get in becoming a Data Scientist
and securing a high paying job You
can read in detail by
going to the link given in the description I hope you
found the information easy and helpful I will
meet you in the next video till then
bye and thanks for watching